epiq11.com 2017-12-22

# Privacy Statement | Epiq

Epiqsystems.com is owned and operated by Epiq Systems, Inc. ("Epiq"). Epiq collects personal and non-personal information on Epiqsystems.com. Epiq is committed to protecting the privacy of its users. We have created this Privacy Statement in order to describe and explain to users our information collection practice. If you have any questions or concerns in connection with Epiq's information collection practice summarized in this Privacy Statement, please send an email, with the subject heading "Privacy Statement Question," to [webmaster@epiqsystems.com](mailto:webmaster@epiqsystems.com?subject=Privacy%20Statement%20Question). In the email, please state your questions or concerns.

### What information is collected?

To participate in certain activities and to obtain certain services offered on this web site, a user is asked to provide varying amounts of personal information. Some information is mandatory while other information is discretionary. Each activity and service requires or requests different types of information in order for users to participate. Activities or services that require provision of personal information generally seek full name, email address, and phone number. Depending on the activity or service a user desires, we also may request additional personal information.

The following is a list of principal activities and services on Epiqsystems.com involving collection of personal information:

### How does Epiq use my information?

Personal information collected, stored, or used as outlined in this policy statement is maintained in accordance with Privacy Shield Principles (see [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/)). Please see our Privacy Shield Policy for further information regarding Epiq’s compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles.

Epiq complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States. Epiq has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

Personal information is collected and used primarily for evaluating job candidates, profiling prospective customers, or building our mailing list for information distribution.

If a user prefers not to receive emails or other forms of communication unrelated to Epiq orders and requests for services, the user may opt-out from receiving such communication by following the hyperlink included in our email correspondence transmissions.

We may also use personal information to contact a user in connection with the user's inappropriate use of Epiqsystems.com.

We do not sell, rent, share, or otherwise dispose of the personal information collected on Epiqsystems.com to third parties. We may, however, disclose your personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such disclosure is necessary to comply with law. Additionally, we provide public-access information about certain consumer and business bankruptcies on epiqsystems.com for the convenience of bankruptcy professionals and for interested members of the public.

We use non-personal information such as demographic data to analyze and develop our marketing strategy. We use non-personal information to determine how you found out about us, what your interests are regarding our services, and how to further improve our site and our service towards you. We also may share non-personal information with third parties.

### Does Epiq's privacy policy apply to linked web sites?

Our Privacy Statement applies solely to information collection practice on Epiqsystems.com. This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Epiq has no control or influence over the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave Epiqsystems.com and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that they visit.

### Changes to this privacy statement

If we later change our Privacy Statement, we will post those changes on our homepage so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

### Consent

By using the Epiq website, you consent to the terms of our online privacy policy regarding the use and processing of personal information, and any and all other terms that may be set forth on our website where Epiq collects personal information.

You further expressly agree that by using this Web Site, your rights and obligations, as well as the rights and obligations of Epiq Systems, Inc. shall be governed, at Epiq's sole discretion, by the laws of the State of Kansas.

### Recourse

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Epiq commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information.  EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Private Shield policy should first contact Epiq at [privacyshield@epiqsystems.com](mailto:privacyshield@epiqsystems.com).

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.
